Guide to the Gay Media Task Force records, 1975-1988
Gay Media Task Force records, 1975-1988
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Gay Media Task Force records, 1972-1988
7315
Gay Media Task Force.
19.6 cubic ft.
Correspondence, press releases, film and television scripts, video tapes.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, press releases and other information of Newton Deiter, coordinator of the Task Force; film and television scripts on which the Task Force worked; 3/4" video tapes of network television programs and source material.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
The Gay Media Task Force was created by the National Gay Task Force in 1972 to serve as a resource organization for network television programming as it addressed gay issues. The collection includes correspondence, press releases and other information about Newton Deiter, coordinator of the Task Force; film and television scripts on which the Task Force worked; erotica; and 3/4" video tapes of network television programs and source material.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Deiter, Newton.
Subjects:
Homosexuality.; Gay men.; Gays.; Television scripts.; Sex on television.; Sex in mass media.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Correspondence
Box 1, folders 1-26
Series II. Newton Deiter Writings
Box 1, folders 27-36
Series III. Film and television scripts
Box 1, folders 37-40
Boxes 3-14
Series IV. Erotica
Box 1, folders 41-50
Box 2
Series V. Videos
Boxes 15-21
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Correspondence
  - 1972-1973 Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1975 Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 2-9)
  - 1976 Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 10-18)
  - 1977 Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 19-23)
  - 1978 Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 24-25)
  - 1979-1987 Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Series II. Newton Deiter Writings
  - Newton Deiter articles, typescripts and manuscripts, published mostly in Insight (Box 1, Folder 27-36)
  - Transcript of 1977 NBC Documentary, "Gay" (Box 1, Folder 37-40)
- Series III. Film and television scripts
  - Dynasty
    - Pilot (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Third Season Bible (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Story Projections, 1985-1986 Season (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Fifth Season Bible (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Bible, 1986-1987 Season (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Episodes 1-35 (Box 3, Folder 6-48)
    - Episodes 36-68 (lacking episode 39) (Box 4, Folder 1-52)
    - Episodes 68-92 (Box 5, Folder 1-44)
    - Episodes 93-120 (Box 6, Folder 1-41)
    - Episodes 121-148 (Box 7, Folder 1-36)
    - Episodes 149-177 (Box 8, Folder 1-36)
    - Episodes 178-195 (Box 9, Folder 1-23)
  - Delaney (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Police Story (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - James Dean: Portrait of a Friend (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Cheers (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - A Nice Girl Like You (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Bronk (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Jigsaw John (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Street of San Francisco (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - The Glitter Palace (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Phyllis (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Boys and Girls Together (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Snip (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - DA's Investigator (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Snip (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Boys and Girls Together (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Snip (Box 10, Folder 8-9)
  - Operation Runaway - The Sexual Image (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Streets of San Francisco (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - The Searcher (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Mulligan's Stew (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Alice (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Dawn: Portrait of a Teenage Runaway (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Maude (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Sanford Arms (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - A Purely Legal Matter (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - The Weekend Hookers (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Let Me In (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Snip (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Dallas (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Hotel (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Hart, Hart, and Harte (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Soap (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Hollywood Cop Scandal (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Boys and Girls Together (Box 10, Folder 27-28)
  - The Boys in the Mailroom (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - The Best Little Boy in the World (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Coming Out (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Consenting Adult (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Hotel (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Coming Out (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Male Model (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - The Searcher (Box 11, Folder 2-3)
  - Police Story (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - The Searcher (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Boys and Girls Together (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - The Weekenders (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Male Model (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Coming Out (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Alexander (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Westside Medical (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Coming Out (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Hotel (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - One Cooks, The Other Doesn't (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Love, Sidney (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Diff'rent Strokes (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Trapper John, M.D. (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Gay (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Journey Home (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - The Boys in the Mailroom (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Teacher, Teacher, I Declare (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - The Glitter Dome (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - The Searcher (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Snip (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Doctors Hospital (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Family (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Sirota's Court (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Gibbsville (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Hot L Baltimore (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Alexander (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - Hotel (Box 11, Folder 31-32)
  - Saturday Before Tomorrow (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - A Cry of Pain (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - Washington, D.C., The Power and the Glory (Box 11, Folder 35)
  - Washington, D.C., The Power and the Glory (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Police Story (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Washington, D.C., The Power and the Glory (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Sirota's Court (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Alexander (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Qwark (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - The Life and Times of Captain Barney Miller (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - CPO Sharkey (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Seventh Avenue (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Lou Grant (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - The Censors (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Ladies' Man (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - It Just So Happens (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - The Boys Next Door (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Shannon (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Double Trouble (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Shannon (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Sidney Shore (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Archie Bunker's Place (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Born Innocent (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Doctors Hospital (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - The Bob Crane Show (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Boys and Girls Together (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Starsky and Hutch (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - The Weekenders (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - The Practice (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Five Women (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Hot L Baltimore (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - The Bob Newhart Show (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Barney Miller (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - The Nancy Walker Show (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - Sergeant Matlovich Versus the U.S. Air Force (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - Washington, D.C. (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - Teacher, Teacher, I Declare (Box 12, Folder 34)
  - Paper Dolls (Box 12, Folder 35)
  - Washington, D.C. (Box 12, Folder 36)
  - Police Woman (Box 12, Folder 37)
  - Serpico (Box 12, Folder 38)
  - Alexander (Box 12, Folder 39)
  - Scruples (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - The White Shadow (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Boys and Girls Together (Box 13, Folder 3-4)
  - Family (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Valentino (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - The Suicide's Wife (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Boys and Girls Together (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Washington, D.C. (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Just Friends (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Boys in the Mailroom (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Police Woman (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Alexander: Portrait of a Teenaged Throwout (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Terraces (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Medical Center (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Barney Miller (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Sirota's Court (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Mary Hartman, Mary Hartman (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Marcus Welby, M.D. "The Outrage" (Box 14, Folder 11)
- Series IV. Erotica
  - Pornographic magazines and photographs (Box 1, Folder 41-50)
  - Five scrapbooks of nude, erotic, and pornographic photographs and drawings (Box 2)
- Series V. Videos
  - 60 Minutes - Rolls Royce Car Report, 1980; V-5866 (Box 15)
  - A Question of Love - Part 1, 1978; V-5867 (Box 15)
  - A Question of Love - Part 2, 1978; V-5868 (Box 15)
  - A Very Natural Thing - Part 1, 1976; V-5869 (Box 15)
  - A Very Natural Thing - Part 2, 1976; V-5870 (Box 15)
  - ABC News Nightline, 1981; V-5871 (Box 15)
  - Alexander: The Other Side of Dawn - Part 1, 1977; V-5872 (Box 15)
  - Alexander: The Other Side of Dawn - Part 2, 1977; V-5873 (Box 15)
  - Alice - "Alice Gets a Pass", Phyllis - "Out of the Closet", 1976; V-5874 (Box 15)
  - All in the Family - "Archie the Hero", Bob Crane Show - "A Case of Misdiagnosis", 1975; V-5875 (Box 15)
  - An Overview of AIDS - CDC, 1983; V-5876 (Box 15)
  - Archie Bunker's Place - "The Cook", 1979; V-5877 (Box 15)
  - Baretta - "The Sky is Falling", 1977; V-5878 (Box 15)
  - Barney Miller - "The Child Stealers", 1980; V-5879 (Box 15)
  - Barney Miller - "Inquisition", 1980; V-5880 (Box 16)
  - Barney Miller - "Movie Part Two", 1981; V-5881 (Box 16)
  - Barney Miller - "Quarantine Part 1", Barney Miller - "Quarantine Part 2", 1976; V-5882 (Box 16)
  - Boys for Sale or Fun and Games in Houston, 1981; V-5883 (Box 16)
  - Bronk - "Deception", 1975; V-5884 (Box 16)
  - C.P.O Sharkey - "Sharkey's Secret Life", NYPD - Episode Unknown, 1977; V-5885 (Box 16)
  - Carter Country - "Out of the Closet", Sanford Arms - "Phil’s Assertion School", 1977; V-5886 (Box 16)
  - CBS Reports - "Gay Power, Gay Politics", 1980; V-5887 (Box 16)
  - Cheers - "The Boys in the Bar", 1983; V-5888 (Box 16)
  - Dallas - "Royal Marriage", 1979; V-5889 (Box 16)
  - Dawn! Part 1, 1979; V-5890 (Box 16)
  - Dawn! Part 2, 1979; V-5891 (Box 16)
  - Death Scream Part 1, 1975; V-5892 (Box 16)
    Digitized, use DVD-719
  - Death Scream Part 2, 1975; V-5893 (Box 16)
  - Doctors' Hospital - "Watchman, Who Will Guard Thy Sleep?", 1975; V-5894 (Box 17)
  - Dynasty - "The Birthday Party", 1981; V-5895 (Box 17)
  - Dynasty - "The Separation", 1981; V-5896 (Box 17)
  - Family - "Rites of Friendship", 1976; V-5897 (Box 17)
  - Family - "We Love You, Miss Jessup", 1977; V-5898 (Box 17)
  - Gay - KNBC Documentary, 1977; V-5899 (Box 17)
  - Gay - KNBC Special, 1977; V-5900 (Box 17)
    Digitized, use DVD-1062
  - Gays: Private Feelings, Public Faces with Malcolm Boyd, 19--; V-5901 (Box 17)
  - Gimme A Break - "The Chief's Gay Evening", 1982; V-5902 (Box 17)
  - Guest Spot - Episodes 33 and 34, 1978; V-5903 (Box 17)
    Digitized, use DVD-1063; includes Newt Deiter interviewing John Birggs about proposition 6 in California.
  - Hot L Baltimore - "George and Gordon", All in the Family - "Judging Books by Covers", 1975, 1971; V-5904 (Box 17)
  - House Calls - "Gays of Our Lives", 1982; V-5905 (Box 17)
  - In the Glitter Palace - Part 1, 1977; V-5906 (Box 17)
  - In the Glitter Palace - Part 2, 1977; V-5907 (Box 17)
  - James Dean - Part 1, 1976; V-5908 (Box 18)
  - James Dean - Part 2, 1976; V-5909 (Box 18)
  - Kiss Me, Kill Me - Part 1, 1976; V-5910 (Box 18)
  - Kiss Me, Kill Me - Part 2, 1976; V-5911 (Box 18)
  - KNBC Special - "Is School Out for Gays?", 1978; V-5912 (Box 18)
  - Ladies’ Man - "An Obtuse Triangle", 1980; V-5913 (Box 18)
  - Lou Grant - "Cop", 1979; V-5914 (Box 18)
  - M.A.S.H. - "George", Barney Miller - "Discovery", 1974, 1975; V-5915 (Box 18)
  - Mary Hartman, Mary Hartman – Episode 127, Sirota's Court - "Court Fear", 1976; V-5916 (Box 18)
  - Maude - "Arthur’s Worry", The Nancy Walker Show - "A Matter of Principle", 1976; V-5917 (Box 18)
  - Maude - "The Gay Bar", Chico and the Man - "The Dress", 1977; V-5918 (Box 18)
  - Medical Center - "Impasse", 1973; V-5919 (Box 18)
  - Medical Center - "Undercurrent", 1970; V-5920 (Box 18)
  - Miscellaneous Clips - Fag Part 1, 19--; V-5921 (Box 18)
  - Miscellaneous Clips - Fag Part 2, 19--; V-5922 (Box 18)
  - Miscellaneous Clips, 19--; V-5923 (Box 19)
    Contains M-M Pornography
  - Police Story - "The Ripper", 1974; V-5924 (Box 19)
  - Saturday Night Live - March 27 Episode, 1982; V-5925 (Box 19)
  - Senior Trip - Part 1, 1981; V-5926 (Box 19)
  - Senior Trip - Part 2, 1981; V-5927 (Box 19)
  - Sergeant Matlovich vs. The U.S. Air Force Part 1, 1978; V-5928 (Box 19)
  - Sergeant Matlovich vs. The U.S. Air Force Part 2, 1978; V-5929 (Box 19)
  - Shannon - "Pilot", 1981; V-5930 (Box 19)
  - Sidney Shorr: A Girl's Best Friend - Part 1, 1981; V-5931 (Box 19)
  - Sidney Shorr: A Girl's Best Friend - Part 2, 1981; V-5932 (Box 19)
  - Snip - "David Makes His Move" and "Out of the Closet", 1976; V-5933 (Box 19)
  - Some of Your Best Friends, 1971; V-5934 (Box 19)
  - Song of Myself, 1976; V-5935 (Box 19)
  - Harry S. Truman: Plain Speaking (labeled as Speaking Frankly) - WQED, 1976; V-5936 (Box 19)
  - Starsky and Hutch - "Death in a Different Place", 1977; V-5937 (Box 19)
  - Stockard Channing in Just Friends - "The Boy in the Band", 1979; V-5938 (Box 20)
  - That Certain Summer - Part 1, 1972; V-5939 (Box 20)
  - That Certain Summer - Part 2, 1972; V-5940 (Box 20)
  - The Associates - "The Censors", 1980; V-5941 (Box 20)
  - The Bob Newhart Show - "A Jackie Story", 1977; V-5942 (Box 20)
  - The Bob Newhart Show - "Some of my Best Friends are...", The Practice - "Helen’s Beau", 1976, 1979; V-5943 (Box 20)
  - The Bold Ones: The New Doctors - "A Very Strange Triangle", 1972; V-5944 (Box 20)
  - The Bold Ones: The New Doctors - Episode, 19--; V-5945 (Box 20)
  - The Last Resort - "Girlfriends", 1977; V-5946 (Box 20)
  - The Naked Civil Servant - Part 1, 1975; V-5947 (Box 20)
  - The Naked Civil Servant - Part 2, 1975; V-5948 (Box 20)
  - The Runaways - "False Images", 1979; V-5949 (Box 20)
  - The Shadow Box - Part 1, 1980; V-5950 (Box 20)
  - The Shadow Box - Part 2, 1980; V-5951 (Box 20)
  - The Streets of San Francisco - "A Good Cop, But...", 1977; V-5952 (Box 21)
  - The Suicide's Wife - Part 1, 1979; V-5953 (Box 21)
  - The Suicide's Wife - Part 2, 1979; V-5954 (Box 21)
  - The Today Show - Gay Media Task Force, 19--; V-5955 (Box 21)
  - The Today Show - "Gays on TV", 19--; V-5956 (Box 21)
  - The Users - Parts 1 and 2, 1978; V-5957 (Box 21)
  - The Users - Parts 3 and 4, 1978; V-5958 (Box 21)
  - The War Widow Part 1, 1976; V-5959 (Box 21)
  - The War Widow Part 2, 1976; V-5960 (Box 21)
  - The White Shadow - "One of the Boys", 1979; V-5961 (Box 21)
  - Trapper John, M.D. - "Straight and Narrow", 1981; V-5962 (Box 21)
  - WKRP in Cincinnati - "Les on a Ledge", 1978; V-5963 (Box 21)
  - Word is Out Part 1, 1977; V-5964 (Box 21)
  - Word is Out Part 2, 1977; V-5965 (Box 21)
  - Copies of 5 U-matic tapes, 719
    Sitcom - Last Resort - Episode Girlfriends, October 5, 1979, :30
    Drama - Medical Center – Episode Impasse, October 1, 1973, 1:00
    TV Movie - Death Scream – March 16, 1977, 1:30 – In two parts, part two the tape colors are off.
    Drama - The Bold Ones: The New Doctors – Episode A Very Strange Triangle, Original airdate October 31, 1972, This broadcast from March 9, 1976, 1:00